Contact

www.linkedin.com/in/aymanhussin (LinkedIn)
my.smartrecruiters.com/
public/profiles/
muhammadnurayman.hussin (Portfolio)

Top Skills

Matlab

Electrical Wiring

ArduPilot

Languages

English (Full Professional)

Certifications

Certified Drone Operation Maintenance Repair Proficient Certified Drone Operation Aerial Surveillance Proficient (Advanced) Board Certification of Graduate Engineer

Honors-Awards

AIMS Exchange Student

Silver Medal Creation, Innovation, Technology & Research Exposition (CITREx) 2020

Ayman Hussin

Electronics, Programming, UAVs, Robotics and Technology Enthusiast

Cyberjaya

Summary

Hi there!

Feel free to connect! Just message me for any inquiries. Thank you! Too passionate toward learning and make research towards new technology - Drones and Robotics

For me working on robotics and UAV drone projects is my intellectual exploration.

Specialties: System of RTK Base Station, Mission Planner, 3D printing, Software In the Loop (SITL), Agriculture Drone, Software, Hardware, Python, Matlab, Robotics (Linux, Robot Operating System, LiDAR, Simultaneous Localisation and Mapping, sensors and actuators), IoT, Machine Learning, image processing, and Artificial Intelligence (Particle Swarm Optimisation, Monte Carlo Method).

Experience

Poladrone

1 year

Embedded System Engineer November 2021 - Present (2 months)

Malaysia

- Take on challenging problems in hardware sensing enablement including distance sensing, UAV localization, navigation, and obstacle avoidance.
- Research and implementation of algorithms on control systems and UAV sensor technology.
- Actively collaborate with drone hardware engineers to optimize design, ensure functionality, support software production tool training and documentation.
- Design experimental flight tests to assess UAV subsystem performance in a real-world environment and provide feedback to technical teams.

• Handle PCB and provide schematic design for PCB for further R&D of UAV.

Electronic Production Technician January 2021 - November 2021 (11 months)

Cyberjaya, Selangor, Malaysia

- Assemble electronic part for agriculture drone
- SMD to PCB soldering
- Setup the ublox GPS/GNSS RTK base station.
- Assist engineer to make improvement on C/C++ Programming & PCB Design.
- Plan and execute drone operations for projects.
- Build and repair UAV that related to software and hardware.
- Ensuring smooth after sales service including repair supply chain.

UAV Pilot cum Technician January 2021 - March 2021 (3 months) Cyberjaya, Selangor, Malaysia

- UAV team lead
- Conduct routine maintenance on UAV drones
- Troubleshoot malfunctioning or defective drones, and repair issues discovered
- Inspect drones for maintenance issues or possible malfunctions before flights
- Assist with the development of simulation exercises designed to test drones for real-word scenarios

PETRONAS

Instrumentation and Control Engineer June 2018 - August 2018 (3 months)

Kertih, Terengganu, Malaysia

- Learnt instrumentation that related to oil and gas plant.
- Servicing and troubleshooting for Instrumentation Maintenance
- Understanding the fitting for every instrument component beside learnt the instrumentation work.
- Understanding Distributed Control System.

Globalmation Sdn Bhd Electrical Technician August 2015 - January 2016 (6 months) Shah Alam, Selangor, Malaysia

- errours manner, e eranniger, menangere
- Servicing and installing Switch Cabinet for machines.
- Learnt read wiring circuit diagram

- Assemble, wiring and conduct testing on system panels.

Education

Asia Drone & IoT Technology
Certified Drone Operation Maintenance Repair
Proficient , Dronepreneur · (2020 - 2020)

UNIVERSITI MALAYSIA PAHANG

B.ENG (HONS.) ELECTRICAL ENGINEERING (POWER SYSTEM), Electrical and Electronics Engineering · (2016 - 2020)

University of Mindanao

Bachelor of Engineering - BE, Electrical and Electronics

Engineering · (2019 - 2019)

UNIVERSITI MALAYSIA PAHANG

Diploma , Industrial Electronics Technology/Technician · (2013 - 2016)